Guide to the Controller, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Controller, Yale University, records
1703-2003
RU 724
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
76.75
The records consist of financial records, committee notes, and correspondence documenting the activities of the Yale controller (formerly comptroller).
Yale University. Office of Finance and Administration
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 5-B (YRG 5-B), Accounting records and records of the Yale comptroller.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See inventory for details
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession
Scope and Contents
The records consist of financial records, committee notes, and correspondence documenting the activities of the Yale controller (formerly comptroller)
Universities and colleges -- Finance; Yale University -- Finance; Yale University. Office of Finance and Administration
- Records, 1968-1980; Accession 1982-A-048 (Box 1–2)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2016
  Scope and Contents
  No online inventory available. Paper inventory available in repository
- Records, 1970-1984; Accession 1985-A-036
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2019
  - Yale College Policy Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - American Council on Education, 1969-1979 (Box 2)
  - Connecticut, State of, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Consortium on Financing Higher Education: Amhurst, Brown, Dartmouth, Harvard, MIT, Mt. Bolyoke, Princeton, Wellseley, Wesleyan, Yale, 1974-1978 (Box 2)
- Financial and audit records, circa 1979-2000; Accession 2002-A-015
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2035
  - Divinity School Financial Statements/work papers, 1994-1998 (Box 6)
  - $16.5 million term loan with Yale Club of New York City - 50 Vanderbilt Avenue, 1997 March 18 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1991 (Box 9)
  - Yale University Financial Statements, 1979-1996 (Box 10)
  - Yale University Management Letter, 1982-1998 (Box 10)
  - Yale Medical School Parking Lot Financial Statements, 1985-1988 (Box 10)
  - Yale Psychiatric Institute Management Letter, 1986- 1992 (Box 10)
  - Yale Psychiatric Institute Financial Statements, 1986-1994 (Box 10)
  - National Science Foundation Grant for Yale Southern Observatory, Inc. FY 1995 Statement (Box 10)
  - Yale OMB Circular A-133 Report, 1993-1998 (Box 10)
  - 1973-1981 (Box 11)
  - 1994 (Box 14)
  - 1990 (Box 14)
  - 1989 (Box 14)
  - 1992-1993 (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - 1996 (Box 15)
  - Yale University Press (Box 15)
  - 1994 (Box 16)
  - 1992 (Box 16)
  - 1993 (Box 16)
  - 1995 (Box 16)
  - 1996-1997 (Box 16)
  - Yale University Press, 1998 (Box 17)
  - Yale Book of Numbers - Historical Statistics of the College and University 1701-1976 (Box 18)
  - New Haven Initiative (Box 20)
  - Yale University Financial Statements, 1992 June 30 (Box 20)
  - Annual Financial Statements and related work papers, 1995 (Box 21)
  - Yale University Financial Statements and related work papers - all documents, 1996 (Box 22)
  - Yale University Financial Statements and related work papers, 1997 (Box 23)
  - Yale University Financial Statements and related work papers (Box 24)
  - Yale Financial Statements and related work papers, 1998 (Box 25)
  - Medical School correspondence, 1994 (Box 26)
  - Annual Report work papers, 1991 (Box 26)
  - Annual Pension Actuarial Valuation Report, 1979-1985 (Box 32)
  - 1996 (Box 36)
  - 1997 (Box 36)
  - 1998 (Box 36)
  - 1995 (Box 36)
  - Commercial Paper, 1997-1999 (Box 37)
- Administrative and financial records, 1962-2002; Accession 2005-A-128
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2078
  - Yale development wire reconciliations, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 74)
  - Yale Press 2002-2003 Employee Benefits (Box 24, Folder 103)
  - 1995 Unclaimed Property - 1999 Filing, 1998-1999 (Box 25, Folder 104)
  - 1996 Unclaimed Property - 2000 Filing, 1996-1997 (Box 25, Folder 105)
  - 1997 Unclaimed Property - 2001 Filing, 1999-2000 (Box 25, Folder 106)
  - 1986 checks, 1985-1986 (Box 26, Folder 120)
  - 1988 checks, 1987-1988 (Box 26, Folder 121)
  - 1995 Escheat A/P - escheat to state, 1994-1995 (Box 26, Folder 122)
  - 1995 payroll escheat reissued checks, 1994-1995 (Box 26, Folder 123)
  - 1996 Escheat A/P - escheat to state, 1995-1996 (Box 26, Folder 124)
  - 1996 Escheat payroll - reissued checks, 1995-1996 (Box 26, Folder 125)
  - 1997 escheat A/P escheat to state, 1996-1997 (Box 26, Folder 126)
  - Disbursements, 1997-1998 (Box 26, Folder 128 - 130)
  - Disbursements - letters of inquiry awaiting replies, 1997-1998 (Box 26, Folder 131)
- Records of the Office of Gift Administration, 1977-1999; 1985-1999; Accession 2013-A-077; Use of the UFMIS-Oracle conversion source numbers in box 35 is required to use the microfiche in this accession.
  Restricted to Office of Origin only
  Microfiche records of the Office of Gift Administration includes: Consolidated Financial Statements; Detailed Transactions by Dept/Fund Sequence; Fund Summary Statements; General Ledger; Year-to-Date Income and Expense; Remaining Balance of Restricted Funds; Remaining Fund Balance; General Appropriations Operating Statements by University, School and Department, 1977-1999 (bulk 1985-1999). Also includes code key binder.
  - 1985 June-1986 March (Box 1)
  - 1986 April-1986 September (Box 2)
  - 1986 October-1987 April (Box 3)
  - 1987 June-1987 October (Box 4)
  - 1987 November-1988 May (Box 5)
  - 1988 June-1988 September (Box 6)
  - 1988 October-1989 March (Box 7)
  - 1989 April-1989 June (Box 8)
  - 1989 July-1990 January (Box 9)
  - 1990 February-1990 June (Box 10)
  - 1990 July-1991 January (Box 11)
  - 1991 February-1991 June (Box 12)
  - 1991 July-1992 January (Box 13)
  - 1992 February-1992 June (Box 14)
  - 1992 July-1993 January (Box 15)
  - 1993 February-1993 July (Box 16)
  - 1993 July-1993 December (Box 17)
  - 1994 January-1994 May (Box 18)
  - 1994 June-1994 September (Box 19)
  - 1994 October-1995 March (Box 20)
  - 1995 April-1995 July (Box 21)
  - 1995 August-1996 January (Box 22)
  - 1996 February-1996 May (Box 23)
  - 1996 June-1996 September (Box 24)
  - 1996 October-1997 February (Box 25)
  - 1997 March-1997 May (Box 26)
  - 1997 June-1997 August (Box 27)
  - 1997 September-1998 January (Box 28)
  - 1998 February-1998 May (Box 29)
  - 1998 June-1998 August (Box 30)
  - 1998 September-1999 January (Box 31)
  - 1999 February-1999 May (Box 32)
  - 1999 June (Box 33)
- Records of the Office of Gift Administration, 1703-2003; Accession 2014-A-013
  Accession 2014-A-013 consists of treasury indentures (now called abstracts) from the Office of Gift Administration which documents a donor's intent/restrictions/preferences on how his/her restricted gift is to be used by the University. Endowment funds are kept in perpetuity.